http://www.pharma-pen.com/privacy-policy

Home
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Manage my Cookies
This Website Privacy Policy explains how West Pharmaceutical Services, Inc. and its subsidiaries (“West”) use and protect any information that you give to us. We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal data. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, transfer, process, use and disclose your data and sets out our security practices.
By using this website, you agree and consent to the transfer, processing, use, and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.
What we collect
We collect personal data that you provide to us, which is information that identifies you as an individual. We do this only when you have agreed to our request for that information. You may withdraw your consent to the processing of your personal data at any time by contacting us (see the “Contact us” section below).
This personal data may include your name, postal address, telephone number, e-mail address, or other information provided by you so that you may receive information about West, register for West programs, contact West customer service, request a Letter of Authorization for reference to a Drug Master File, respond to West surveys, make purchases from West's Online Store or for reasons related to West’s legitimate business interests of improving and enhancing our products and services.
We may also collect information about your visits to West websites without you actively submitting such information. For example, unidentifiable information may be collected using various technologies such as cookies. Your internet browser automatically transmits to our websites some of this unidentifiable information, such as the URL of the web site you just visited and the browser version on which your computer is operating. Passive information collection technologies can make your use of our websites easier by allowing us to provide better service, customize sites based on preferences, compile statistics, analyze trends, and otherwise administer and improve our websites. Certain features of our websites may not work without use of passive information collection technologies. Information collected by these technologies cannot be used to identify you without additional identifiable information.
How we use personal data
West will use personal data that you agree to provide to us to respond to your queries, to provide information or access to online resources you have requested, to complete your purchases, and to provide you with efficient customer service. West may also use personal data to market products and services that we think may be of interest to you, but only in accordance with local privacy or e-marketing laws, to enforce compliance with this website’s terms of use or to protect our service, website or other users.
Website and mobile application usage information
We also automatically collect information about your computer browser type and operating system, websites you visited before and after visiting our websites, standard server log information, and Internet Protocol (IP) addresses.
How we protect your personal data
When handling your personal data, we take reasonable measures to protect that information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction.  In the event that we are required by law to inform you of any unauthorized access to your personal information we may notify you electronically, in writing, or by telephone, if permitted to do so by law.
When we may transfer your personal data
We will not sell, share, or otherwise distribute your personal data to third parties except as provided in this Privacy Policy.
Personal data collected from you may also be transferred in the following situations:
Corporate affiliates.  West is a global group of companies that has databases in different countries. We may transfer your data to other West affiliates worldwide or to one of the company’s databases outside your country of domicile, potentially to countries whose laws may not require the same level of protection for your personal data compared with that provided in your country. Such West affiliates agree to treat your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. West has entered into controller to controller Standard Contractual Clauses (SCCs) globally which govern and protect the transfer of data from the EU West entities to West entities outside the EU.
Service providers. Personal data may be transferred to third parties who act for or on our behalf, for further processing in accordance with the purpose(s) for which the data were originally collected or may otherwise be lawfully processed, such as services delivery, evaluating the usefulness of this website, marketing, payment processing, data management or technical support. These third parties have contracted with us to only use personal data for the agreed upon purpose and have agreed not to sell your personal data to third parties, nor to disclose it to third parties except as may be required by law, as permitted by us or as stated in this Privacy Policy.
Acquisitions and corporate change.  Personal data may be transferred to a third party in the event that West or a part of it and the customer data connected with it is sold, assigned or transferred, in which case we would require the buyer, assignee or transferee to treat personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.   Personal data may also be sold in the event that we contemplate, anticipate, or are exploring such a transfer.
Legal reasons. Personal data may be disclosed in response to subpoenas, warrants, discovery requests, or court orders, or in connection with any legal process, or to comply with relevant laws.  We may also share your information in order to establish or exercise our rights, to defend against a legal claim, to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding possible illegal activities, suspected fraud, safety of person or property, or a violation of our policies.
Other disclosures with your consent.  Personal data may be disclosed in other situations in which you provide us with the consent for the disclosure.
In order to protect the transfer of personal data from the EEA to a third party located outside the EEA, West uses adequate safeguards, such as the Standard Contractual Clauses.
Use of IP addresses
West, or third-party companies acting on our behalf, may collect IP addresses for the purposes of systems administration and to audit the use of our websites. We also may use IP addresses to identify users of our websites when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with the websites’ terms of use or to protect our service, websites or other users.
Cookies
Manage my Cookies
Our websites and mobile applications may use technology called "cookies." A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a server. Cookies allow our websites and mobile applications to respond to you as an individual. The website or mobile application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. For instance, our server may set a cookie that keeps you from having to enter a password more than once during a visit to a website. We also permit third parties to place technology on our websites, such as cookies, that may allow them to track you over time and across different web sites.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies or receive a warning before a cookie is stored if you prefer. Please refer to your Internet browser’s instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions and to specify your cookie preferences.
If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of our website.
In order to register for an account on our website, you must provide the minimum amount of personal data requested, including your name and email address, and functional, analytics and targeting cookies will all be deployed upon successful registration. By completing and submitting a registration request, you are indicating your consent to the use of these cookies, which are necessary, in part, to provide you with relevant content and to help us authenticate you as the person who should have access to your West account. These cookies also enable us to collect data on the technical interests of our site visitors so we may continue to provide personalized content.
Information from outside sources
Where permitted by local law, we may collect legally obtained information from third parties to add to our existing user databases. Some of this information may be personal data. We do this to better target information offerings and promotional campaigns in which we think you would be interested. Such personal data will only be collected and used by us in accordance with the legal basis on which it was originally provided by the subject, or as otherwise permitted by local law.
Data retention, right of access, objection, correction, deletion and portability
We will retain your information only for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. You may contact us to request to access (in a portable format or otherwise), update, correct, or remove personal data, to object to our continued processing of your data, to revoke consent to our processing of data (where our processing is based upon consent).   Contact information is provided at the end of this Privacy Policy. In the case of electronic direct marketing, we will provide you with a method to opt out of receiving further marketing materials or with a method to opt in if required by law. Requests to delete personal data will be subject to any applicable legal and ethical reporting or document filing or retention obligations imposed on us.
We do not discriminate against individuals who exercise any of the rights described in this policy.
Information for California Residents
California Civil Code Sections 1798.115(c), 1798.130(a)(5)(c), 1798.130(c), and 1798.140 indicate that organizations should disclose whether certain categories of information are collected, “sold” or transferred for an organization’s “business purpose” (as those terms are defined under California law).  You can find a list of the categories of information that we collect and share here. Please note that because this list is comprehensive it may refer to types of information that we share about people other than yourself. If you would like more information concerning the categories of personal information (if any) we share with third parties or affiliates for those parties to use for direct marketing please submit a written request to us using the information in the "Contact Information" section below.  We do not discriminate against California residents who exercise any of their rights described in this Privacy Policy.
We do not sell consumer (as defined in the California Consumer Privacy Act) personal information to third parties.
Automated decision-making
Automated decisions are defined as decisions about individuals that are based solely on the automated processing of data and that produce legal effects that significantly affect the individuals involved. As a rule, West does not make automated decisions for personal data. If automated decisions are made, affected persons will be given an opportunity to object to them.
Links to other websites
Our websites and mobile applications may from time to time provide links to or embed third party websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to those websites. If you choose to enter such a linked site, you agree that we are not responsible for the availability of such websites and do not review or endorse and shall not be liable, directly or indirectly, for how these websites treat and use your personal data, or for the content and use of the websites.
Accessibility of website
This policy is currently uploaded to our website as HTML and, as a result, should be accessible to audio-readers.
Use of our websites and mobile applications by children
West is committed to protecting the privacy of children. We do not knowingly collect personal data from visitors under the age of 13.
Changes
We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy. If the changes are material, we may post a notice regarding the changes on our websites or mobile applications and related licensing agreements. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal data we collect. Subsequent changes in this Privacy Policy will not necessarily apply to data that were collected before the change was made, unless required by law.
Contact us
• For any questions, comments and requests for correction, deletion and portability of your data pursuant to the European General Data Protection Regulation or the California Consumer Privacy Act, please complete our Personal Data Request Form.
• Please address any other questions regarding this Privacy Policy to:
Susan Morris
Senior Counsel & Chief Compliance Officer
530 Herman O. West Drive
Exton, PA 19341 USA
Email: Integrity@westpharma.com
Toll-free Number:  1-800-345-9800
Be sure to include information on how you can be contacted.
Complaints
If you feel that West has violated EU legislation relating to data protection, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority located in the EU.
Last reviewed and updated November 17, 2020.
Asia - Pacific (China)
Asia - Pacific (China)
Asia - Pacific (Others)
Asia - Pacific (Others)
Asia - Pacific (China)
Asia - Pacific (China)
Asia - Pacific (Others)
Asia - Pacific (Others)
Asia - Pacific (China)
Asia - Pacific (China)
Asia - Pacific (Others)
Asia - Pacific (Others)
Asia - Pacific (China)
Asia - Pacific (China)
Asia - Pacific (Others)
Asia - Pacific (Others)
